字幕翻译制作：goodliuwu
不可饶恕
她是个清秀的年轻女人，不是没有前途
所以 她后来嫁给威廉・曼尼的时候
她母亲的心碎了
威廉・曼尼，是个知名的盗贼、谋杀犯
恶名远扬 凶残成性
她死的时候，并非如她母亲可能会想的那样
死在他手上
她死于天花  那是1878年
怀俄明州 大威士忌 1880年
（台球 楼上）
真小
It's small!
不，求你了，不要！
No, please. No! Please!
戴维!
Davey!
快过来，小子！
Come running, lad!
- 住手！ - 给你刻个印，烂婊子！
-Stop! -Brand you like a damn steer bitch!
不要，求你了！
No. Please!
抓住这个婊子！戴维，抓住她！
Hold the bitch! Go on, hold her!
抓住她，该死，我要把她的奶头切下来！
Hold her, damn it, or I'll cut her tits off!
快去叫瘦皮！快！
Go get Skinny! Quick!
迈克，不要！
Mike, don't!
瘦皮!
Skinny!
你觉得它可笑吗？
Think it's funny?
瘦皮
Skinny
拿枪来
get the gun!
放开她，牛仔
Get off of her, cowboy.
不让你管这事儿？
Wouldn't let you settle it?
你知道瘦皮的为人
You know Skinny is.
他说他要毙了他们
He says he'll shoot them.
我说：瘦皮，你不能这么做
l says, "Skinny, you can't do that. "
他说：那就去叫小比尔来处理这事
He says, "Get Little Bill in here to settle this thing."
我说：小比尔在睡觉
l says, ''Little Bill's sleeping. ''
他说他不管，再过五分钟他就杀了那俩小伙子
He says he don't care. Another 5 minustes, he'll shoot them boys.
她会死吗？
She going to die?
她会活下来的
She's gonna live.
她什么也没偷，甚至没碰过他的钱袋
She didn't steal nothing. She didn't even touch his poke.
她做的 只是看见他的小小鸟儿时...
All she done is when she seen he get a teensy little pecker...
笑了几声，就这样
...she's given giggled. That's all.
她不知道这样不好
She didn't know no better.
你要吊死他们，小比尔
You can hang them, Little Bill.
克莱德
Clyde.
去办公室 把牛鞭拿来
Step over to the office and get the bullwhip.
一顿鞭打？他们做下这种事就挨顿鞭子？
A whipping? That's all they get after what they done?
这不算小了，艾丽丝
It ain't no little thing, Alice.
- 但是他们做的...  - 艾丽丝！
-But what they done... - Alice
闭嘴！
Shut up!
小比尔
Little Bill
鞭打解决不了这事
Whipping ain't going to settle this.
不够吗？
No enough?
这份合法合同，我和蒂莱拉・菲茨杰拉德的，那个被割的妓女
Here's a lawful contract between me and Delilah Fitzgerald, the cut whore.
我从波士顿把她带过来，替她出了全部费用
l brought her here from Boston, paid her expenses and all.
我这份合同 代表了一项资本投资
l got contract that represents an investment of capital.
财产
Property.
被损坏的财物
Damaged property.
就像我弄跛了他们的一匹马
Like if I hamstrung one of their ponies.
你觉得现在没人愿意操她了，对吧？
You think nobody wanna fuck her now, right?
见鬼，当然！
Hell, no!
至少没人愿意付钱干！
At least won't pay to do it!
也许她能弄好脸蛋
Maybe she can clean up her face
但没人会为一个被割过的妓女付好价钱
but nobody's going to pay good money for a cut-up whore!
你俩被赶出巴提了
You boys are off the Bar T.
你们自己有马吗？
Got your own string of ponies?
有，我有四匹
Yeah, I got four.
六匹
Six.
我想你们更愿意不审理，不反对吧？
You just as soon not have a trial, no fuss?
没有，长官
No, sir.
好了
All right.
是你割的
You did the cutting.
秋天过来，你带五匹马，全都给这个瘦皮
Come the fall, you bring in five ponies and you give 'em all to Skinny here.
五匹？
Five?
还有你，你带两匹来
And you! You bring in two.
- 你们要交出来，听见没？  - 是，长官
-You give them over, hear? -Yes, sir.
鞭子，比尔
The bullwhip, Bill
也许我们现在不需要这鞭子了
Maybe we don't need this whip now.
我告诉你们
Let me tell you
到了春天，瘦皮还没拿到那些马...
come the spring, Skinny don't have those ponies... .
我会来找你们
I'll come looking for you.
你连打都不打他们了？
You ain't even gonna whip them?
我用罚款代替了，艾丽丝
l fined them instead, Alice.
他们干了这种事，瘦皮得到几匹马，这就完了？
For what they done. Skinny gets some ponies and that's it?!
这不公平，小比尔
That ain't fair, Little Bill
这不公平
That ain't fair.
这一晚上你还没见够血吗？
Haven't you seen enough blood for one night?
见鬼，艾丽丝!
Hell, Alice!
他们又不是流浪汉、游民或坏人...
It ain't like they was tramps or loafers or bad men
你知道，他们只不过是...
you know, they were just...
努力工作的孩子，做了蠢事
hardworking boys that were foolish.
- 要是他们以某种方式邪恶一下，我并不...  - 比如招妓？
-If they was given over to wickedness in a regular way, I don't... -Like whores?
艾丽丝!
Alice!
去照顾蒂莱拉
Tend to Delilah.
去吧
Go ahead
我有85元
l got $85.
我不知道
l don't know.
如果蒂莱拉怎么都不在乎，我们干嘛这么生气？
If Delilah doesn't care one way or the other, what we are get so riled up about?
我们让这些臭傻瓜把我们当马骑...
Just because we let them smelly fools ride us like horses...
并不代表我们要让他们把我们当马烙印子
...don't mean we let them brand us like horses.
也许我们是什么都不如的妓女
Maybe we ain't nothing but whores,
但我们…老天，我们并不是马
but, by God, we ain't horses!
我有112元
l got $1 1 2.
这是全部了
That's everything.
你呢，阿贞?
How about you, Faith?
200.
240元
$240
天呀！阿贞，你都做些什么？
Jesus, Faith! What you been doing?
给瘦皮什么特殊服务了？
Been giving Skinny something special?
她笑了
She laughs.
有了凯特的、茜丽的，我的以及小苏…
With what Kate got, and Silky got some, and my and Little Sue--
还不够
It ain't enough.
只是目前不够
Not yet, maybe.
你看起来可不像牛逼闪闪的...
You don't look like no rootin'-tootin' ...
狗娘养的冷血杀手
son of a bitching cold-blooded assassin.
你说什么？
Say what?
我猜想 你自称是威廉・曼尼先生吧
My guess is you call yourseIf Mr. William Munny.
你把我和别人弄混了，先生
You have me confused with someone else, mister.
就是那个在湖县枪杀查理・佩珀的人
The same one who shot Charlie Pepper in Lake County?
爸，喂，爸
Pa! Hey, Pa!
在，怎么了，儿子？
Yeah. What's up, son?
又有两头猪得了热病
Two more hogs got the fever.
是你枪杀了查理・佩珀，对吧？
You shot Charlie Pepper. Didn't you?
就是你杀了威廉・哈维，然后劫了密苏里那趟火车
You're the one who killed William Harvey and robbed that train in Missouri.
等一下，先生
Hold on, mister.
儿子，你把那些猪隔离开
Son, you get those hogs separated there.
佩妮，我要你帮帮你哥哥
Penny, I want you to help your brother out.
那只也病了
That one's sick too.
对
Yeah.
我们到里面谈
We'll talk inside.
那么你是皮特・索肖的侄子？
So you're Pete Sothow's nephew?
我还以为你可能是来杀我的呢
l thought maybe you're someone come to kill me
为了我往日曾做过的事
for something I'd done in the old days.
我也可能是
l could have.
放松
Easy.
我想可能是吧
l guess maybe so.
就像我说的 你看来不像是凶神恶煞的冷血杀手
Like I was saying. You don't look like no meaner-than-hell, cold-blooded, damn killer.
也许我不是
Maybe I ain't.
皮特叔叔说 你是活着的最凶神恶煞的杂种
Uncle Pete says you was the meanest goddamn son-of-a-bitch alive.
如果我想要个杀人的伙伴...
And if I wanted a partner for a killing...
你是最坏的一个
you were the worst one.
意思是最好的
Meaning the best.
你像冰雪一样冷酷无情...
On account as you're as cold as snow...
你从不脆弱也不害怕
you don't have no weak nerve nor fear.
这是皮特说的？
Pete said that?
对，他是说过
Yeah. Yeah, he did.
我自己也是个杀手，只不过...
I'm a damn killer myseIf, except...
没你杀人多，因为我还年轻
l haven't killed as many as you because of my youth.
斯科菲尔德小子，他们就是这么叫我的
Schofield Kid, that's what they call me.
为什么？
Why?
你是斯科菲尔德来的？
You from Schofield?
不，只因为我的...
No, it's on account of my...
斯科菲尔德型史密斯・威森手枪
Schofield model Smith & Wesson pistol.
怎么样，威尔?
How about it, Will?
什么怎么样？
How about what?
做我的搭档怎么样？
How about being my partner?
我要向北穿过奈厄布拉勒 到怀俄明去
I'm heading north through Niobrara to Wyoming
去杀两个坏牛仔
to kill a cauple no-good cowboys.
为了什么？
For what?
因为割伤了一位女士
For cutting up a lady.
划花了她的脸
Cut up her face.
挖出她的眼睛，割掉她的耳朵
Cut her eyes out, cut her ears off.
他们甚至割了她的乳头
They even cut her titts.
天啊！
Jesus!
1000美元赏金，威尔
$1 ,000 reward, Will.
每人5百
500 apiece.
爸
Pa.
我拉不动那些该死的猪
l can't move those damn pigs!
别咒骂好吗，
Watch your cussing, will you?
尽力去做，然后去水泵那儿洗干净
Do the best you can with it. Then go to the pump and get yourself cleaned up.
快去
Come on.
我再也不那样了，小子
l ain't like that anymore, Kid.
以前的事全是威士忌作祟
It was whiskey done it as much as anything else.
我已经滴酒不沾十多年了
l ain't had a drop in over 10 years.
我的妻子，她治好了我
My wife, she cured me of that.
治好了我的醉酒和邪恶
Cured me of drinking and wickedness.
你看起来不太发达
You don't look so prosperous.
你可以给她买条新裙子，用你那一半赏金
You could buy her a new dress with your haIf.
要是我们杀了他们两个，你能给你妻子买条漂亮的…
If we kill them, you can buy your wife one fancy--
她过世了
She's passed on.
什么？
What?
到现在走了快三年了
Been gone near 3 years now.
不要告诉别人赏金的事
Don't tell no one else about the reward now.
我不要别的枪手去争取
I don't need other gunmen trying to collect.
我们在这里谁也见不着
We don't see no one out here.
如果你改变主意，你可以来追我...
If you was to change your mind, you can catch me
我往正西方骑行追踪...
I'll be riding due west for the trail
向北往怀俄明去
Heading to north and Wyoming.
来吧，我们把那些猪分开
Come on, let's separate those hogs.
爸
Pop
还有两只
Two others.
我想他们得了热病
l think they got the fever.
你们可花了不少时间
Took you boys a while.
再多过几天，我就要报告治安官了
A couple more days and I was going to call on the sheriff.
怎么样？
How about that?
河水全涨了，我们渡不过去
The river was all swelled up. Couldn't cross it.
可不是，瞌睡虫，把这些马带到马房去
l bet. Sleepy, get them horses to the livery.
尼尔，把这匹带到后面去
Neil, take that one over around the back.
噢，这里有个美人
Now there's a beauty.
你已经得到我两匹马了，这匹不是你的
You got two of mine. This one here ain't yours.
我们走着瞧
We'll see about that.
混蛋！滚出镇子！
Bastards! Get out of town!
你们都是婊子养的变态！
You are very sick sons of bitches!
不要再回来，屠夫！
Don't come back, butcher!
这匹小马...
This here pony...
给那个被我伙伴割伤的女士
l brung for the lady my partner cut.
它是最好的一匹
She's the best of lot.
比我给他的强多了
Better than ones I gave him.
她可以卖掉它或者...
She can sell her or...
想怎么样都行
or do what she wants.
一匹马？
A pony?
她的脸都毁了，你就给她一匹该死的脏马？
She ain't got no face left, you gonna give her a goddamn mangy pony?
它不脏，夫人
She ain't mangy, madam
滚出这地方！
Get out of here!
我们不需要你该死的施舍！
We don't need your goddamn charity!
滚出我们镇子，永远不要回来！
Get out of our town and don't come back!
滚出我们镇子！
Get out of our town!
爸以前杀过人？
Did Pa use to kill folks?
克劳迪娅・费瑟斯・曼尼
生于于1849年5月11日
卒于1878年8月6日 享年29岁
佩妮，我可以告诉你，你妈以前喜欢我给她的花
Penny, I could tell your ma liked those flowers I gave her.
它不再是鞍马了，爸
He ain't a saddle horse no more, Pa.
不习惯那种感觉了
Ain't used to the feel.
照顾好你妹妹，儿子
You take care of your sister, son.
必要的话你就杀几只鸡，另外…
And you kill a few chickens if you had to and...
把那些得了热病的猪隔离
Keep those hogs got the fever separate.
如果你有什么问题，去内德・洛根家找“两树萨莉”
If you have any problem, you go see Sally Two Trees at Ned Logan's.
我自己也有段时间没坐过马鞍了
Ain't been in the saddle myseIf in a while.
这匹马在跟我扯平我年轻时犯下的罪过
The horse's getting even with me for the sins of my youth.
我年轻时，遇见你们过世的亲爱妈妈之前...
ln my youth before I met your dear departed ma...
我那时有缺点，还惯于虐待动物
l used to be weak and given to mistreating animals.
来吧
Come on.
这匹马，还有那边那些猪...
This horse and those hogs over there...
在扯平我过去对它们的残忍
are getting even for the cruelty I inflicted.
我以前会咒骂和鞭打这样的马匹，但是…
I used to be able to cuss and whip a horse like this, but...
你们的妈妈，愿她安息，让我看到了自己的错误
your ma, rest her soul, showed me the error of my ways.
我两星期后回来
I'll be back in a couple of weeks.
记住 你们过世的亲爱妈妈在天之灵在照顾你们
You remember how the spirit of your dear departed ma watches over you.
你们哪里弄来的钱？
Where'd you get that money?
我们没什么钱
We ain't got any money!
- 你跟那些牛仔说你有钱！  - 我们骗人的
- You told them cowboys you had! - We was lying!
骗人？
Lying?
有人来领钱你怎么办？
What're you gonna do if somebody comes to collect?
你准备让他们搞？
Are you going to hump them?
你准备让他们搞一千次？
You going to hump them a thousand times?
来拿一千块钱的那种人可忍不了你没钱
The kind of people who come for a thousand won't tolerate you not having it!
他们不会只划划你的脸！
They won't just cut up your face a little!
你们这些蠢婊子
You stupid bitches.
你们这些蠢婊子！
糟糕
Shit!
该死的，天啊！
Damn it! Jesus!
打到手指了？
Hit your finger?
你好，瘦皮.
Hello, Skinny.
该死，你跟踪我？
Damn, you snuck up on me.
你觉得它如何？
What do you think of her?
我听说你自己做的屋顶
Well, l heard you done the roof yourseIf.
屋顶？
Roof?
老天爷，瘦皮，其实这该死的东西全是我自己做的
Jesus, Skinny, I did practically the whole damn thing myseIf.
罗伯茨家的孩子，帮我搬搬木头，就这些了
The Roberts boy, he carried some wood for me, but that's all.
那些木头是做什么的？
What is all that wood?
建走廊用的
That's for my porch.
我要盖个走廊，晚上就能坐在这里...
I'm buiding a porch so I can sit of an evening...
抽抽烟斗，喝喝咖啡，看看日落
and smoke my pipe and drink coffee and watch the sunset.
大老远过来就为看它一眼？
Came all way out here just to take a look at her?
- 唉，那些妓女！  - 怎么？
-Them whores! -Yeah?
那些妓女最近两周一直在跟那些来镇上的牛仔们搞
Those whores been humping them cowboys who been in town the last 2 weeks.
真糟糕，瘦皮.
Shit, Skinny.
你看
You know.
我们有铁路大亨，有养牛大亨
We got our railroad barons. We got cattle barons.
你快成我们的第一位台球大亨了
You'll be the first billiard baron.
是啊，她们一边搞一边告诉每一个罗圈腿...
Yeah, well. They been humping and telling every bowlegged one of them that...
她们会出一千美元 给无论哪个混蛋...
they'll pay $1 ,000 to whoever son of bitch...
只要他杀了那两个 割伤蒂莱拉的牛仔
kills the two boys that cut up Delilah.
那些牛仔，是赶牛去堪萨斯和夏延的吗？
Those cowboys are riding that beef down to Kansas and Cheyenne?
是
Yeah.
多久了，整周内？
How long, all week?
我自己是直到昨晚才听说的
Well, I didn't hear till last night myseIf.
见鬼，话现在恐怕已经一路传到德克萨斯了
Hell, the word's probably got all the way down to Texas by now.
糟糕，比尔，我想从德克萨斯来的人都不会不带枪了
Shit, Bill, I guess nobody'll come clear from Texas.
你确定这些妓女有那一笔钱？
You sure those whores they got all that money?
你知道女人们喜欢说慌
Well you know women can lie.
稍微敲打她们一下，问她们钱在哪？她们说没有
Knock 'em around a little bit. Ask 'em where the money is, they say they ain't got none.
但她们可能偷偷存下来，她们五个
But they could squirreled away 'em, those five of them.
也许
Maybe.
有那么多？
That much?
你可以赶走那两个牛仔
You could run off them two cowboys.
我能赶走那些妓女
l could run off them whores.
我猜想他们反正已经跑了吧，那两个牛仔
Well I guess they'll just up and run anyhow, them two.
没有
No.
他们待在巴提
They'll stay out at the Bar T.
和他们的朋友在一起
Close to their friends.
靠，比尔，也许根本不会有人来
Shit, Bill, could be nobody won't come at all.
得走了，我喜欢你的房子
Well, got to go. I like your house.
喔，见鬼了...
Well, I'll be...
是威尔!
It's Will!
嘿，威尔
Hey, Will.
进屋躲躲阳光
Come in the house out of the sun.
内德
Ned.
萨莉
Sally...
看好威尔的马
see to WilI's horse.
萨莉
Sally
你来这干嘛，威尔？
What are you doing here, Will
只是觉得应该顺路来看看你
Just thought I'd drop in on you.
威尔，我们可不再是坏人了
Yeah, Will, we ain't bad men no more.
应该是农民
Should be farmers.
杀他们应该容易
Should be easy killing them
我觉得，我不知道，如果他们不先去德克萨斯的话
I surppose, I don't know, if they don't go on down to Texas.
你多长时间没朝人开枪了，威尔
How long has it been since you fired a gun at a man, Will?
九年，十年？
Nine, ten years?
十一年
Eleven.
容易？
Easy, huh?
即便在过去 我也不知道有那么容易
l don't know it was all that easy even back then.
那时我们还年轻 充满活力
And we were young and full of beans.
我是说，如果你恼恨他们，威尔...
I mean if you was mad at them,  Will, I mean...
如果他们做错了什么，我可以理解射杀他们
If they done some wrong, I could see shooting them.
我们以前为钱干过，内德
We done stuff for money before, Ned.
我们以为如此
We thought we did.
好了，这俩人做了什么？
All right, so what'd these fellows do?
打牌作弊？
Cheat at cards?
偷牲口？
Steal some strays?
对有钱人吐口水？是什么？
Spit on a rich fellow? What?
不，他们割了一个女人
No. They cut up a woman.
什么？
What?
对，割了她的脸，挖出她的眼睛
Yeah. Cut up her face, cut her eyes out
割掉她的手指，割掉了她的乳头
Cut her fingers off, cut her tits.
所有一切，除了她的阴户，我估计
Everything but her cunny, I suppose.
我勒个去
I'll be dogged.
我想他们是罪有应得
Guess they got it coming.
当然你也知道，威尔...
Of course, you know, Will...
如果克劳迪娅还活着，你不会做这事的
if Claudia was alive, you wouldn't be doing this.
别这么假设
Don't suppose you don't mind.
下周你能照顾下我的孩子吗？
Could you look in on my youngsters next week?
他们要隔离一些猪
They got some hogs they're trying to separate.
威尔
Will
你要离开多久？
How long will you be gone?
两个星期，我想
Two weeks, I guess.
威尔
Will.
那个小子，他怎么样？
This Kid, what's he like?
分三份？
Three ways?
我看见你还留着那支斯宾塞来复枪
I see you still have that Spencer rifle.
对
Yeah.
而且我还能把飞鸟的眼睛打出来呢
And I can still knock the eye out of a bird flying too.
天啊，威尔!
Jesus, Will!
他肯定是不停地走
He must be moving right along.
我们明天就能赶上他，我估算
We'll come across him tomorrow, I reckon.
有点习惯睡床上了
Kind of got used to my bed.
这跟没有家的时候不一样了
This ain't going to be like no home.
床不是我唯一想念的东西，我告诉你
That ain't the only thing I'm gonna be miss, I tell you.
威尔，对不起
Ah, Will, I'm sorry.
别担心，这没什么
Don't fret it. It ain't nothing.
她不太喜欢，对吧？
She doesn't like it much, does she?
你和我一起骑马离开
you riding off with me.
萨莉?
Sally?
用恶毒的目光看我
Gave me the evil eye.
你知道的，萨莉是印地安人...
You know, Sally's injun...
印地安人不会过于友好，威尔
and injuns ain't over-friendly, Will.
我不怪她
I don't blame her.
我不会拿这一点针对她
I won't hold it against her.
她早先就认识我
She knew me back then.
她知道我是个...
She knew what a...
多么坏的混蛋
no-good son of a bitch I was.
她只是不愿承认我改变了
She just ain't allowing that I changed.
她没意识到我再不像以前那样了
She don't realize I ain't like that no more.
- 你知道女人的  - 我不一样了，内德
-You know women. -I ain't the same, Ned.
克劳迪娅，她矫正了我
Claudia, she straightened me up.
帮我戒了威士忌和其它
Cleared me of drinking whiskey and all.
单凭我这一次去杀人...
Just 'ause I'm going on this killing...
并不是说我要变回过去那样
don't mean I'll go back to be in the way I was.
只是需要钱
Just need the money.
让孩子们有新的开始
Get a new start for them youngsters.
是啊
Yeah.
内德，你记得那个我对着他嘴里开枪的牲口贩子吧？
Ned, you remember that drover I shot in the mouth...
牙从脑袋后面崩出来
and his teeth came out the back of his head?
- 记得  - 我不时想起他
- Yeah. - I think about him now and again.
他没干什么，不该被枪杀
He didn't do anything to deserve to get shot.
起码等我清醒之后 想不起有什么
At least nothing I could remembered when I sobered up.
你以前是个疯子混球，威尔
You was one crazy son of a bitch, Will.
对，没有人喜欢我，小伙子们都认为我会...
No one liked me and the boys all thought I was...
纯出于邪性而枪杀他们
gonna shoot them out of pure meanness.
你再也不像那样了
You ain't like that no more.
“老鹰”，他恨我入骨
Eagle, he hated my guts.
波拿巴对我想得不多
Bonaparte didn't think too much of me there.
昆西也是，我估计
Quincy neither, I reckon.
昆西以前总是在旁边看着...
Quincy used to just watch all the time...
吓坏了
scared.
就像我说过的...
Like I said...
你再也不像那样了
you ain't like that no more.
是的
That's right.
我现在只是个平常人
I'm just a fellow now.
我跟其他人没有什么不同...
I ain't no different than anyone else...
再也不了
no more.
（西北铁路）
我只想知道是哪个混蛋枪杀了他？
I just wanna know what son of a bitch shot him as all?
（“加菲尔德总统情况危急”）
是不是那些英国佬？
Was it one of them John Bulls?
不是，先生
No, sir.
我相信那个可能的暗杀者是个法国血统的绅士
I beleive the would-be assassin is a gentleman of French ancestry.
看来如此
Or so it seems.
我作此评论并无冒犯之意...
I don't wish to give offense when I observe...
但法国人是出名的“暗杀种族”
but the French are known to be a race of assassins...
而枪法不值一提
who can't shoot worth a damn.
当然，这里在场的法国人排除在外
Any Frenchmen present company are excluded, of course.
这里说有个叫做吉托的家伙，G-U-I-T--
Says here a fellow by the name of Guiteau. G-U-l-T--
在我听来 就是个地道的英国佬
Sure as hell sounds like a John Bull to me.
虽然如此，依然无意冒犯...
Though so, again, I don't wish to give offense
但我想建议这个国家应该选择
when I suggest this country select...
一位国王，或甚至女王，也好过一位总统
a king or even a queen, rather than a President.
没人这么快就刺杀国王或女王
One isn't that quick to shoot a king or a queen.
王室的威严，了解吧
The majesty of royaIty, you see.
也许你本意不想冒犯，先生...
Maybe you don't wish to give offense, sir...
但你正在大大的冒犯
but you are giving it pretty thick.
这个国家根本不需要女王什么的
This country don't need no queens whatsoever.
不管什么鬼时候我听到女王...
No matter the heck when I heard about queens--
闭嘴，乔
Shut up, Joe.
你有什么毛病，老渴？这狗娘养的老兄--
What's wrong with you, Thirsty? This dude son of bitch--
这位老兄可能是“英国人鲍勃”
Might be that this dude here is English Bob.
他为铁路公司工作，专门射杀中国佬
He's the one works for the railroad shooting Chinamen.
可能他正等着哪个傻牛仔伸手拔枪...
Might be he's waiting for some crazy cowboy to touch his pistol...
他就可以开枪击倒他呢
so he can shoot him down.
那是事实吗，先生？
Is that a fact, mister?
你是“英国人鲍勃”?
You English Bob?
山鸡
Pheasants.
我们来打山鸡吧
Let's shoot some pheasants.
10枪
Ten shots.
这么说吧，一美元一只
At, let's say, $1 a pheasant.
我为女王而射击，你们则为...
I'll shoot for the Queen, and you for...
随便谁吧
well, whomever.
我打了8只，你打了1只
That's eight for me and one for you.
那就是7美元
That comes to seven American dollars.
打得真他妈好...
Pretty damn good shooting...
作为一个英国佬来说
for a John Bull.
豪无疑问，你的准头受到悲伤情绪的影响...
No doubt your aim was affected by your grief...
因为你们的总统受伤
over the injury to your President.
是气候导致的，气候，还有可怕的远距离
It's the climate that does it. That, and the infernal distances.
导致什么？
Does what?
导致人们对高层人物开枪
Induces people to shoot persons in high places.
你知道这是个野蛮的国家，真的
You know it's a saverage country, really.
这是20年里他们枪杀的第二个总统了
That's the second they shot in twenty years.
（不准火器进入大威士忌 包括手枪和来复枪）
这不文明，射杀要人
It's uncivilized shooting persons of substance.
谢谢你
Thank you.
请原谅我，先生们
Pardon me, gentlemen.
本地法律要求你们在此逗留期间 向有关机构交出所有随身武器
The local law obliges you to surrender all sidearms to the proper authorities during your vist.
有关机构？
Proper authorities
我向你保证，年轻人
Well I'm gonna assure you, young man
我的同伴和我都没有随身携带火器
that neither my companion or I carry firearms on our person.
我们依靠的是与人为善...
We rely upon the goodwill of our fellow man...
以及爬虫般的忍耐
and the forbearance of reptiles.
没有武器个鬼！
Unarmed, my ass!
天啊，真热！
Christ, it's hot!
如果我要挨枪子，我宁愿在热天而不是冷天
If I'm going to get shot, I'd rather it was hot than cold.
冷天里所有东西的杀伤力都会增加
Everything hurts me more when it's cold.
你知道的当伤到你的大拇指...
You know how if you hit your thumb when it's cold...
闭嘴，胖子!
Shut up, Fatty!
克莱德回来了
Clyde's back.
- 小比尔和他一起？  - 没有
-Little Bill with 'im? -No.
该死！
Shit!
- 你们清洗了我的雷明顿？ - 清洗而且装弹了
-You boys clean my Remington? -Cleaned and loaded.
老天在上，小比尔在哪里？
Where's Little Bill for Christ sake?
在建他该死的走廊呢
Building his damn porch.
建他的走廊？
Building his porch?
如果你中枪，安迪，你更愿意在热天还是冷天？
If you got shot, Andy, would you like it better on hot day or cold day?
我不会中枪
I ain't going to get shot.
他会来吧？
He's coming?
当然他会来
Of course he's coming.
我刚装好子弹，你干嘛？
I just loaded that. What're you doing.
我信不过别人给我的枪上子弹，是我开枪
I trust nobody loading my guns if I'm shooting.
他说什么？
What did he say?
小比尔吗？他没说什么，我说了他正在盖走廊
Little Bill? He said nothing. I said he was building his porch.
你见过那东西吗？
You seen that thing?
都装好子弹了
It was all loaded.
老天，克莱德
Jesus, Clyde
你拿了三支手枪，可你只有一条胳膊，老天爷
you got three pistols and you only got one arm, for Christ sake.
我只是不想因为不能还击而送命
I don't want to get killed for lack of shooting back.
知道吗，他那整个烂走廊的角度都不直！
You know he don't have a straight angle on that whole god damn porch!
整个房子都是这样
Or the whole house, for that matter!
他是最糟糕的烂木匠
He is the worst damn carpenter.
他什么也没说？
He didn't say nothing?
只问了他们长什么样，就这些
Asked what they looked like, that's all.
可能他很牛逼，但他确实算不上木匠
Christ, maybe he's tough but he sure ain't no carpenter.
可能他没那么牛逼
Maybe he ain't so tough.
他看着像是害怕了？
Seem like he was scared?
小比尔？他害怕了？
Little Bill? Him scared?
我们从来没见过他对付像这样的人
We never seen him up against any like these ones.
杀手
Killers.
小比尔从堪萨斯和德克萨斯来的，伙计们
Little Bill come out of Kansas and Texas, boys.
他在狠地方待过
He worked them tough towns.
我只是想知道
Just wondered.
任何人都会害怕
Anybody could be scared.
他不会害怕的，伙计们
He wasn't scared, boys.
他只是干不好木匠活儿
He just ain't no carpenter.
王室的权威有一种尊严...
There's a dignity in royaIty of majesty...
它排除了刺杀的可能性
which precludes the likelihood of assassination.
如果你用手枪指着一位君王
Now, if you pointed a pistol at a monarch.
你的手就会像中风一样颤抖
your hands would shake as if palsied.
我不会用枪指着任何人，先生
l wouldn't point no pistol at nobody sir.
这是聪明的策略，聪明的策略
That's a wise policy. A wise policy
但如果你这么做，我可以跟你保证，如果你做了
But if you did, I can assure you, if you didi.
王室的意象会导致你打消所有杀戮的念头
The sight of royaIty would cause you to dismiss all thoughts of bloodshed.
而你会站在那里...
You would stand...
该怎么说呢...
how should I put it...
充满敬畏
in awe.
然而
Now...
一位总统...
A President... .
我说，枪杀总统有何不可？
I mean, why not shoot a President?
- 不用找了 - 谢谢
-Keep the change. -Thank you
这个叫“草莓艾丽丝”的人，再跟我说一次
This Strawberry Alice person, tell me again.
走到街尾路口，格里利啤酒馆和台球厅
Down the street in the cross to Greely's Beer Garden and Billiards Parlor.
就找艾丽丝，就说你想打场台球
Just ask for Alice. Say you want a game of billiards.
打台球？即使我并不真的想打？
Billiards? Even though I don't really wish to play?
没关系，78年他们把球台当木柴烧了
No matter. They burned the table in '78 for firewood.
太对了
Quite right.
博尚先生，我想一杯茶会...
Mr. Beauchamp, I think a cup of tea would...
你好，鲍勃
Hello, Bob.
伙计们，这位是英国人鲍勃
Boys, this here is English Bob.
狗屎煎鸡蛋！
Shit and fried eggs!
好久不见，鲍勃
Been a long time, Bob.
中国佬都杀光了？
Run out of Chinamen?
小比尔
Little Bill
我还以为你...我以为你死了呢
I thought that you were...I thought you were dead.
我看你把你的山羊胡剃了
I see you've shaved your chin whiskers off.
留着胡子喝完汤两小时还能尝到味
I was tasting the soup two hours after I ate it.
实际上，我听到的是，你...
Actually, what I heard was you...
从马上掉下去，当然，喝醉了
fell off your horse, drunk, of course.
你折断了该死的脖子
And that you broke your bloody neck.
这一则我自己也听说过，鲍勃
I heard that one myseIf, Bob.
见鬼，我也以为我死了呢
Hell, I even thought I was dead.
直到发现 自己在内布拉斯加
Till I found out I was just in Nebraska.
你的朋友是谁？
Who's your friend?
- W.W. 博尚  - 博尚
- W.W. Beauchamp. - Beauchamp
这位是小比尔・达格特
This is Little Bill Daggett.
还有些朋友，当然
And friends, of course.
达格特
Daggett
哪认识的，牛顿，海斯？阿比林？
From Newton, Hays? From Abilene?
面对面
In person.
你也为铁路工作，博尚先生？
You work for the railroads too, Mr. Beauchamp?
不
No
我写东西，我写…
I write. I write...
写信？
Letters?
书，比尔，写书
Books, Bill. Books.
实际上...
Actually...
他是我的自传作者
he's my biographer.
我是你的话，就不会这么做
I wouldn't do that if I were you.
博尚先生
Mr. Beauchamp
只是一本书
It's only a book.
一本书？
A book?
我想这就是说你们识字了
I guess that means you boys can read.
我想也就是说 你们见到了外面的标语
I guess that means you saw the signs outside town
上写交出火器
saying surrender your firearms.
可是就像你跟这位年轻的安迪说的...
But like you told young Andy...
你没带武器，是吧，鲍勃？
you're not armed, are you, Bob?
不全是，比尔
Not really, Bill.
带了把“决斗者”，但它不会让你担心的，对吧
Got a Peacemaker, but that wouldn't worry you, would it?
我是说如果你没看见，或更确切来说没听说它
If you don't see it. Or most perticulally, if you don't hear it.
我恐怕要担心，鲍勃
I'm afraid so, Bob.
我不喜欢周围有火器
l don't like firearms around.
千万要小心，孩子
Be very careful with it, sonny.
查理
Charley
看看博尚先生的包里是什么样的书
See what kind of books Mr. Beauchamp is packing there.
小心别沾湿了
Make sure you don't get wet.
什么也没有，小比尔
No shit. Little Bill.
他这里都是些文具和这本书
All he's got here is writing stuff and this book.
《死亡公爵》
“死亡公鸭”？
"The Duck of Death"?
呃，“公爵”
"The Duke. "
“公爵”，比尔
"The Duke", Bill.
好了，午安，先生们
Well, good afternoon, gentlemen.
我还要那把点32，鲍勃
I'll have that .32, Bob.
现在，小比尔...
Now, Little Bill...
你让我只能寄望于我的敌人发善心了
you will leave me at the mercy of my enemies.
敌人吗，鲍勃？
Enemies, Bob?
你又在谈女王了？
You been talking about the Queen again?
在独立日
On Independence Day?
我想你以为我是在踢你吧，鲍勃
I guess you think I'm kicking you, Bob
不是这样的！
But it ain't so!
我现在 是在说话！
What I'm doing is talking!
你听见没？
Do you hear?!
对所有那些堪萨斯过来的坏蛋说！
Talking to all them villains down here in Kansas!
对所有那些密苏里的坏蛋说！
To all those villains in Missouri!
对那些...
And those villains...
夏延的坏蛋说！
down in Cheyenne!
我在告诉他们 这里没有妓女的赏金！
I'm telling 'em there ain't no whore's gold!
即便有，他们也不要想来拿...
Even if there was, they don't want to come for it...
无论如何
anyhow!
你们都看什么？
What are you all looking at?!
赶快走开！
Go on get outta here!
去操心你们自己的事！
Go on mind your own business!
威尔
Will
你去过镇上么？
You ever go into town?
有时，卖掉一只猪，买点生活用品
On occasion. To sell a hog, pick up supplies.
不不，我是说...
No no, I mean...
我是说，给自己找个女人什么的
I mean, get yourseIf a woman or something.
不，我绝不会为这事去镇上的
No, I never go into town for that.
像我这样的男人
A man like me?
我这样的男人能得到的女人，只能是付钱得到的
Only woman a man like me could get is one I'd have to pay for.
这不对，买肉体
That ain't right, buying flesh.
克劳迪娅，愿她安息，绝不想要我做这种事...
Claudia, rest her soul, would never want me doing some like that...
我是一个父亲
...me being a father and all.
那...
So...
你，你就用手？
You just use your hand?
我并不是太想念这事
I don't miss it all that much.
威尔
Will
- 该死！有人向我们开枪！  - 对
-Goddamn! Somebody's shooting at us! -Yeah
糟糕
Oh, shit!
打到你了？
Did it hit you?
没，我从马上掉下来撞到头
No, I bumped my head falling off my horse.
不再对我们开枪了
Ain't shooting at us no more.
朝那边射的
Shooting way over yonder.
他到底在射那边的什么？
What the hell's he shooting at over there?
这可真把我问倒了
Beats the hell out of me.
估计我们进了某人的土地，你说呢？
Reckon we in somebody's field, do you?
我没看见种了什么东西
I didn't see nothing planted.
又对我们开枪了
Shooting at us again.
他在朝整个视线范围开枪，威尔
He's shooting at the whole horizon, Will
喂
Hey!
等一下，你把我们暴露了！
Wait a minute! You'll mark us!
喂，小子！
Hey, Kid!
小子？
Kid?
你是说对我们开枪的就是那小子？
You mean that's the Kid shooting at us?
小子，是我！威尔・曼尼!
Kid, it's me! Will Munny!
这小子向我们开枪搞什么鬼？
What the hell's the kid shooting at us for?
是你吗?
Is that you?
对
Yeah!
对，是我！
Yeah, it's me!
不要再朝我们开枪了！你听到没有？
Don't go shooting at us no more! You hear me?
你带来那人是什么鬼，威尔?
Who the hell you got with you, Will?
他是内德・洛根，我的老搭档
It's Ned Logan, my old partner!
别再冲我们开枪了，听到没有？
Don't go shooting at us, you hear?
我们准备牵上马走过去
We're gonna collect our horses and come on over there.
你不会再开枪，对吧？
You ain't going to shoot, are you?
不会了
No!
不会，我不会了！
No, I ain't!
追踪那匹马有他妈一里路
Chased that horse a damn mile.
你对我们开枪干什么？
What the hell was you shooting at us for in there?
我以为你们在跟着我
I thought you was following me.
我们是在跟着你
We was following you.
就像你说的，如果我改变主意...
Like you said if I changed my mind...
我可没说要什么搭档，威尔
Wasn't nothing said about no partner, Will.
这位内德・洛根
This here's Ned Logan.
这位是斯科菲尔德小子，彼特・索肖的侄子
He's the Schofield Kid, nephew to Pete Sothow.
我看到两个人跟着我，我猜你们要来杀我
I seen two fellows following me. My guess is you come to kill me.
咱们可没说过叫别人来
We never talked about no other fellow.
他们那边是两个牛仔，对吧？
Well, there's two of them cowboys, isn't there?
我们有三个人会好些，万一他们有朋友的话
Better there's three of us, incase they got friends.
我估计自己能搞定他们两个牛仔
I figure I can take care of them two cowboys myseIf.
不用三个人
It don't take three.
内德用来复枪准得可怕，能打中飞鸟的眼睛
Ned's an awful good shot with a rifle. Hit a bird in the eye flying.
一半都比你强，小子
Better than you in half, Kid.
见鬼，你还差的远呢
Hell, you wasn't even close.
你那该死的手别碰我的来复枪，先生
Get your damn hands off my rifle, mister.
只想替你检查一下，也许什么东西弯了
Thought I'd check it for you. Thought maybe something was bent.
没有弯曲
It ain't bent.
可你刚才在四处乱射！
Well you were shooting all over creation!
你愿意和他分你的一半？
You'll share your half with him?
我想分三份
I figure three ways.
你想错了
You figured wrong.
抱歉，我浪费你的时间了，内德
Sorry I wasted your time, Ned.
什么，你和他一起回去？
What, you going back with him?
他是我的搭档
He's my partner.
他不去，我也不去
He don't go, I don't go.
怎么分呢，三份？
What's it come to, three ways?
该死！
Shit!
你在骂什么？
What are you pissing on about?
什么？
What?
- 还有你在看什么？ - “看”？
-What are you looking at, anyhow? -"Looking at"?
云，小子
Clouds, Kid.
看见它们，就知道有风暴要撵我们屁股了
Looking at them clouds on account of we got a storm riding up our ass.
哦，那些
Oh, there
见鬼，我也看到了
Hell, I seen them.
你改主意是聪明的，小子
You was smart to change your mind, Kid
- 是吗？  - 是的
- Yeah?  - Yeah.
用这支来复枪，我能射得很准
I'm a real good shot with this rifle.
看到上面那只鹰了吗？
See that hawk up there?
我能一枪把那只鹰打下来
I could hit that hawk with one shot.
我也能打中它，内德
Hell, I could hit it too, Ned.
只要不介意浪费子弹
If I didn't mind wasting a shot.
天上没鹰，小子
There ain't no hawk, Kid.
你屁都看不见，对吧？
You can't see for shit, can you?
看到你的水壶了吗？
See your canteen?
好了，你能看多远？
All right, how far can you see?
足够远了
Far enough.
我们不是要去射水壶！该死的，多远？
We ain't goning wild to shoot canteens! God damn it, how far?
- 100码？  - 更远
-100 yards? -More.
- 你能看见远处那棵冬青栎吗？  - 操你妈，内德
-See that scrub oak tree yonder? -Fuck you. Ned.
他是瞎的，威尔
He's blind, Will.
我不瞎！你这混蛋！
I ain't blind, you asshole!
等一下，住手
Now, hold on. Hold it!
你能看多远，小子？50码？
How far can you see, Kid? 50 yards?
你可以赌上性命，我当然能看50码，威尔
You bet your ass I can see 50 yards, Will.
我看得够清楚了 打死我面前这狗杂种是够了
I can see well enough to shoot this son of a bitch right here in front of me.
住手
Hold on.
你听到没，内德?
You hear that, Ned?
小子能看50码，可以了
Kid can see 50 yards. Fine.
老天！
Jesus!
50码已经可以了，我们现在走吧
50 yards'll do just fine. Now let's move out.
看起来真是艰苦的战斗，鲍勃
They look like real hard cases, Bob.
你把他们7个都杀死了？
Did you kill all seven of them dead?
还是只伤了其中几个？
Or did you just wing some of them?
刻在封面上的是你吧？
That you here embalmed on the cover?
“死亡公鸭”？
"The Duck of Death"?
“公爵”，“死亡公爵”
The Duke. "Duke of Death. "
“公爵”，是哦
Duke. Oh, yeah
你的手枪总是使得出神入化，鲍勃
You always were the hell of Jesus with a pistol, Bob.
但他们有7个人，鲍勃...
But seven of them, Bob...
而你还要保护那女的，你是怎么做到的？
And you're protecting that woman. How do you do that?
你瞧...
You see, awu...
在出版业里，杂志社认为这是可取的...
It's journal consider desirable in the publishing business to take a certain...
在描绘封面时有一定的自由发挥
liberty when you're depicting the cover scene.
主要是牵涉到市场原因
Just for reasons involving the marketplace--
那是胡扯
Well it's bullshit.
从我读的这些来看，内容和封面所画没有太多不同
From what I read this here, the writing's not that much different than the picture.
我可以跟你保证，达格特先生...
Well I can assure you, Mr. Daggett...
所描述的事件都是来自目击者的诠释
that the events described are from eyewitness accounts.
目击者？
Eyewitnesses?
是的先生
Yes sir.
你是说，像是“公鸭”本人，是吧？
You mean, like the Duck himseIf, I guess.
“公爵”
The Duke.
“公鸭”，我说了
Duck, I says.
“‘你侮辱了这位美丽女士的清誉，科克伦...’”
"'You have insuIted the honor of this beautiful woman, Corcoran...'
“公鸭说道”
said the Duck.
“'你必须道歉'”
'You must apologize.'
“但双枪科克伦根本不理会”
But Two-Gun Corcoran would have none of it.
“咒骂着，他伸手去掏枪，要杀了他...”
Cursing, he reached for his pistols and would have killed him...
“...但是公鸭更快，他冒烟的六发枪火光一闪”
...but the Duck was faster and hot lead blazed from his smoking six-guns. "
你看，我认为这就是对事件的真实描写
You see, I consider that an accurate depiction of events.
老实说，语言上是有些诗意 这是我情不自禁的
I'll be honest. There is a certain poetry to the language which I couldn't resist.
博尚先生
Mr. Beauchamp
我也在维奇托的蓝瓶酒吧...
l was in the Blue Bottle Saloon in Wichita...
就是英国人鲍勃杀科奇・科克伦的那个晚上
the night English Bob killed Corky Corcoran.
我没看见你在那里
I didn't see you there.
也没有女人
Nor no woman.
也没有双枪射手
Nor two-gun shooters.
这些都没有
Nor none of this.
你在场？
You were there?
对，我在场
Yeah, I was there.
第一...
First of all...
科奇从不带双枪，尽管他本来应该带
Corky never carried two guns, though he should have.
他被叫做“双枪科克伦”
He was called Two-Gun Corcoran.
很多老乡的确叫他“双枪”
A lot of folks did call him Two-Gun,
但不是因为他带有两把手枪
but not because he was support two pistols.
而是因为他的老二实在太大...
It was because he had this dick was so big...
比他带的那把沃克柯尔特的枪管还长
was longer than the barrel on his Walker CoIt.
而且他干的唯一侮辱人的事
And the only insulting he ever did...
就是用他那东西 插了一位法国女士...
was stick that thing his into this French lady
而这位英国人鲍勃正爱着她
that English Bob here was sweet on.
你看，那晚科奇走进蓝瓶
You see the night that Corky walked into the Blue Bottle
还不知道怎么回事呢...
before he knew what's happen...
这位鲍勃就向他开了一枪
Bob here takes a shot at him!
可他没打中，因为他太他妈醉了
And he misses, because he's so damn drunk.
子弹嗖地飞过吓坏了科奇
That bullet whizzing by panicked Corky.
于是他做了一件错事
And he did the wrong thing.
他太着急掏出枪，击中了自己的脚趾
He went through his gun such a hurry and shot his damn toe off.
同时，这位鲍勃...
Meantime, Bob here...
他认真瞄准，再次扣动扳机...
He's aiming real good and he squeezes off another...
但他又射失了！
but he misses,
因为他还是太醉了！打中酒吧那头一面1千美元的镜子！
'cause he's still so damn drunk! And he hits this $1 ,000 mirror over the bar.
但现在，死亡公鸭就要死了...
But now, the Duck of Death is as good as dead...
因为科奇做对了
because Corky does it right.
他瞄得很仔细
He aims real careful.
- 不慌不忙  - 然后呢？
-No hurry. -And?
那支沃克柯尔特在他手里炸膛了
That Walker CoIt blew up in his hand
这是那种型号的通病
Which was a failing common to that model.
你看，要是科奇真有两把枪 而不是一根大老二的话
You see if Corky'd had two guns instead of just a big dick
他本可以在那里防卫自己到底了
he would've been there right to the end defend himseIf .
等一下
Wait a minute.
你是说，英国人鲍勃杀了他，是在他甚至没有...
You mean that English Bob killed him when he didn't even have... .
老鲍勃可不会等科奇再长出一只新手
Old Bob wasn't going to wait for Corky to grow a new hand.
不，他只是很慢地走过去...
No, he just walked over there real slow...
因为他醉了...
because he was drunk...
一枪打穿了他的肝脏
and shot him through the liver.
该死，我不喜欢石头硌着我该死的背！
Damn. Don't like rocks on my dadgum back!
我可真想念我的床
I sure do miss my bed.
你昨晚就说过了
You said that last night.
我知道，昨晚我说我想念我老婆
I know. Last night I said I missed my wife.
今晚，我只是想念我该死的床
Tonight I just miss my dadgum bed!
下回就该想念你该死的屋顶了，我估计
You'll miss your dadgum roof next, I suppose.
该死！
Shit!
我说，威尔
Say, Will
杰克逊县的那件事...
That business up in Jackson County...
真的发生过吗？
that really happen?
我是说 像他们说的那样？
I mean the way they say it happened?
什么事？
What business?
两个副治安官 近距离用他们的来复枪对着你
I mean how these two deputies up close pointing their rifles right at you.
把你盯死了
Got you dead to rights.
你拔出手枪，把他俩轰进地狱
You pulled out your pistol and blew them to hell.
只用了一个掏枪动作
Only took a scratch yourseIf.
皮特叔叔说 从来没见过这样的...
Uncle Pete said he never seen nothing like it...
你那一下子开枪的方法
shooting your way out of that scrape.
是啊
Yeah.
我不回忆
I don't recollect.
你不回忆？
You don't recollect?
是的
That's right.
我说内德...
Say, Ned...
你杀过多少人？
How many men you killed?
你不准备回答这问题吗？
Aren't you gonna answer the question?
这和你有什么鬼关系？
What the hell's that to you?
我得了解与我同骑的是什么人
Well, I gotta know what kind of fellow I'm riding with
万一我们要干一仗什么的
in case we get into a scrape and all.
你杀过多少人，小子？
How many men you killed, Kid?
5个
Five!
多少？
How many?
5个！
Five!
我杀过五个人
I done killed five of them.
包括一个墨西哥人，他拿着刀追我
That's including a Mexican. He come after me with a knife.
你能闭嘴吗，休息一下
Why don't you shut up? Get some rest.
你们俩怪得像一对老母鸡，我告诉你们
You boys are as crotchety as a couple of old hens. Let me tell you.
所以其实，科克伦先生…
Actually, then, Mr. Corcoran
拔枪要快过“公鸭”...
was faster on the draw than the Duck--
英国人鲍勃？
Than English Bob?
更快？更快就是他犯的错误
Faster? Faster was his mistake.
他要不是天杀的那么着急
If he hadn't made such a god damn hurry
第一枪也不会打中自己的脚趾
he wouldn't have shot his toe on that first shot.
他本该杀了老鲍勃的
He would've killed old Bob.
瞧，孩子
Look, son
要当一个好枪手，出手迅速...
Being a good shot, I mean quick with a pistol...
没什么坏处，但远比不上头脑冷静
that don't do no harm, but it don't mean much next to being cool-headed.
一个人保持头脑，不在火力下慌张...
A man who'll keep his head, not get rattled under fire...
多半他就能杀了你
like as not he'll kill you.
但如果另一方更快，先开枪...
But if the other fellow is quicker and fires first...
那他就会着急，然后就失手
Then he'll be hurry and he'll miss.
看好了
Look here.
这是我拔枪、瞄准、打中十码外目标的最快速度
That's as fast as I can draw, aim, hit anything more than 10 feet away.
除非这是个谷仓
Unless it's a barn.
但要是他没有失误呢？
But if he doesn't miss?
那他就会杀了你
He'll kill you.
所以危险人物才那么少，比如老鲍勃
That's why there's so few dangerous men around like old Bob.
比如我
Like me.
想要射击一个人没那么容易
It ain't so easy to shoot a man you know.
特别那些会还击的人
Especially some's shooting back at you.
我是说，那会惊起几个老乡
I mean that'll flat rattle some folks.
我给你看样东西
Let me show you something.
等等
Just...
- 这儿，拿着这个  - 好的，稍微…
- Look here. Take that. - I know, just...
来呀，拿着
Go on, take it.
这是钥匙
There's the key.
你只需要开枪打我...
All you gonna do is shoot me
你和鲍勃就能骑马离开这里，像鸟一样自由
and you and Bob can ride on out of here free as birds.
已经…已经装弹了？
Is it loaded?
不装子弹它还有什么用
Wouldn't do much good if it wasn't.
首先，你得扳起枪机
First, you got to cock it.
来呀，扳起来
Go on, cock it.
现在你得对准
Now you got to point it.
快呀，对准呀
Go on. Point it.
现在你要做的就是扣动扳机，先生
Now all you got to do is pull the trigger, mister
烫手，对吧？
Hot, ain't it?
你手指都没放到扳机上
Didn't even put your finger on the trigger.
假如，假如...
What if... .
假如我把枪给他呢？
What if I gave it to him?
给他
Give it to him.
你不是真的想...
You don't...you don't really...
把枪给他
Give it to him.
我看他并不想要，博尚先生
l guess he don't want it, Mr. Beauchamp
你不拿它是对的，鲍勃
You were right not to take it, Bob
不然我已杀了你
I'd have killed you.
我们需要一点雨，博尚先生
We could use some rain, Mr. Beauchamp
老天，你这没用、该死、猪操的妓女！
For God sake, you no-good, goddamn pig-fucking whore!
抱歉，老马
Sorry, old horse.
我带着这个 想等到杀了他们再喝
I brung this alone for when we kill them fellows.
估计我们现在可以喝点
Figured we could use some now.
我不要，我再也不碰那玩意了
Not me. I don't touch it no more.
得了威尔，下着雨呢
Come on, Will, it's raining.
我知道在下雨！
I know it's raining!
何不给那孩子一点儿？
Give some to the Kid, why don't you?
你觉得那孩子真的杀了五个人？
You think that Kid really killed five men?
不
No
你知道
You know...
当他说那一次
When he talked about the time
那些副治安官用枪指着你的时候
them deputies had the drop on you... .
哦
Yeah
我记得你射杀了三个人，威尔，不是两个
I remember there was three men you shot, Will, not two.
我再也不像那样了，内德!
I ain't like that no more, Ned!
我不再是疯狂杀人的傻子了
I ain't no crazy killing fool.
仍然觉得杀那些牛仔很简单吗？
Still think it'll be easy to kill them cowboys?
只要我们不先被淹死
If we don't drown first.
把这钥匙交给管理员
Give these keys to the conductor.
告诉他，一出了本县就可以把鲍勃的手铐解开
Tell him he can loose Bob's cuffs as soon as he's outside the county.
我的手枪呢？
Got my pistols?
我估计你知道，鲍勃...
I guess you know, Bob...
如果我再看见你，我会开枪自卫
that if I see you again I'm just gonna start shoot in seIf-defense.
我可没有抢走你的传记作者！
I didn't steal your biographer!
他自愿留下来的！
He's staying on his own account!
他也可以自己寻找素材，是不是？
He can go stuff himself as well, can't he?!
愿瘟疫降临你们这些臭烘烘的人
The plague on the whole stinking lot of you!
没有道德和法律！
Without morals or laws!
还有你们这些妓女！你们没有原则，你们没有名誉
And all you whores! You got no laws. You got no honor!
怪不得你们都移民到美国！
It's no wonder you all emigrated to America!
就因为英国容不下你们
Because they wouldn't have you in England!
你们都是野蛮人！就是你们
You're a lot of savages! Yes you all
同一族血腥的野蛮人！
You're all a bunch of bloody savages!
诅咒你们！
A curse on you!
我会回来的
I'll be back
没人会来了...
Nobody's going to come...
小比尔这样对付这个英国人以后
after what Little Bill done to that Englishman.
蒂莱拉，桌子不干净，你不能去把它们擦干净吗？
Delilah, those tables ain't clean. Can't you get them tables clean?
也许你把脸遮起来就会有人愿意干你，你就不用做清洁了
Maybe you cover your face, somebody might hump you and you wouldn't have to clean.
那种遮脸的东西叫什么来着？
What do they call that thing to cover face with?
面纱
A veil.
对，面纱，去弄个面纱！
Yeah, veil. Get a veil!
雨来了
Rain's coming
谢天谢地
Thank God.
威尔
Will
你确定？
You sure?
你没事吧，威尔?
You all right, Will?
（法令：大威士忌不得携带火器）
有个家伙点名要你，艾丽丝
Fellow asking for you, Alice.
今晚？你不是开玩笑吧？
Tonight? You ain't joshing?
这边，先生
This way, mister
这种天气还出来，真是急色鬼
Must be randy as hell to come out in this shit.
“不，不！你错了，小比尔”！他说
"No, no! You're wrong, Little Bill" ! he said.
“那不是卷发，那是平头"
"That's not a Curly J. That's a Bobbed J! "
他改了发型，我就对他说...
He had changed it over. And I said to him...
"吉姆，你是骗子和偷马贼！”
"Jim, you're a liar and a horse thief! "
他发现其他人不准备帮助他时
When he saw the rest of them wouldn't help him none
他就开始哭了...
he started crying...
一边抽泣，一边求情
and sobbing and just carrying on.
他说，“上帝，比尔，求你，不要杀我，比尔!"
He said, "God, please, don't kill me, Bill! "
于是我说："吉姆，你真让我恶心..."
So I said, "Jim, it makes me sick... "
- 你能打开窗吗？  - 好
-Open the window, will you? -Yeah
“看到一个人，带着两把手枪，一支亨利来复枪...
" ...to see a man carrying two pistols and a Henry rifle...
哭得像个他妈的婴儿”
and crying like a damn baby. "
所以你杀了他？
So you killed him?
没有
No
不过我应该杀他的
But I should have.
我不能忍受这类人
I can't abide them kind.
你看见他们在酒馆里
You see them in the taverns, you know.
徒步者、醉酒的车夫
Tramps and drunk teamsters.
发狂的矿工
Crazed miners.
摆弄着他们的手枪，装作坏人的样子
Sporting their pistols and acting like they was bad men.
可是既没有风沙有没有个性
But without any sand or character.
连不良习性都没有
Not even any bad character.
- 我不喜欢搞暗杀的  - 暗杀
-I do not like assassins. -Assassins
- 还有那些品格低下的人  - 对
- Or men of low character. - Yes.
就像你的朋友，英国人鲍勃
Like your friend, English Bob.
- 可是，鲍勃不是个懦夫，你知道  - 不是
-But, now Bob was no coward, you know. -No
他不会到你面前哭，不停地那样…
He wouldn't come up to your face and cry and carry on like that--
治安官，我没法...
Sheriff, I just...
哦，该死，我没有再多容器了
Yeah, damn. I don't have any more receptacles.
也许你吊死那个木匠得了
Maybe you should hang the carpenter.
什么？
What?
我这样说是因为...要是你吊...
l was just saying because of the...If you hang...
没事了
Doesn't matter.
搞什么鬼？
What the hell?
在这种天气里！
On a night like this!
是他妈谁？
Who the hell is it?
副治安官查理・赫克，比尔
Deputy Charley Hecker, Bill.
什么事
What?
三个人刚进了镇，比尔
Three fellows just come into town, Bill.
他们去了格里利的店
They're down to Greely's.
他们有两人带着枪
There's two of them got guns.
是什么绊住了那小子？
What the hell's keeping that Kid?
你看他不是在...
You don't suppose he's up..
天啊，威尔!
Jesus, Will!
你看起来一团糟
You look like shit.
你记得“老鹰”亨德肖特吗？
You remember Eagle Hendershot?
对
Yeah.
我看见他了
I saw him.
威尔，他死了
Will, he's dead.
不，我看见他了，内德
No, I saw him, Ned.
他的脑袋整个被打烂了，你能看到里面
His head was whole broke open. You could see inside of it.
老天，威尔，你发烧了
Jesus! You got a fever.
- 喝杯酒 - 虫子从里面爬出来
-Take a drink, will you?  -Worms were coming out of it.
那个，威尔，我要上去看看是什么绊住了那小子
Look, Will, I wanna go up to see what's keeping the Kid.
一定是在哪位运动女士身上收预付款呢
Must be getting an advance from one of the sporting ladies.
那个，如果我要...
Look, if I was to...
我是说如果可以，我就自己也乐一乐...
I mean, if it worked out that I could take a little time for myseIf
我想你会...
I'm supose you would
我是说你不会...
I mean you wouldn't...
我估计你不愿意来
I guess you don't want to come.
手枪给我，先生
Give me the pistol, mister.
我说把你的手枪给我
I says give me over your pistol.
我没醉
I ain't drunk.
法令说你必须上交你的火器给县办公室...
Ordinance says you got to turn in your firearms to county office...
不论白天晚上
day or night.
我猜想你没看见布告牌，因为这天气什么的
I guess you didn't see the sign, wiht the weather and all.
没有
No.
但我没有...
But I ain't...
我没有武器
I ain't armed.
你那些在楼上的朋友呢？他们带手枪了吗？
What about your friends upstairs. They got any pistols?
不，我想...
No, I guess...
不，他们...他们也没有武器
No, they...They ain't armed either.
你的威士忌洒出来了
Spilled your whiskey.
瞧，我...
Look, I...
你叫什么？
What's your name?
威廉..
William...
...亨德肖特
...Hendershot.
好吧，威廉・亨德肖特先生...
Well, Mr. William Hendershot...
如果我说你是个狗娘养的没用骗子会怎么样？
...what if I was to say you was a no-good son of a bitching liar?
如果我说 你因为胆小如鼠拉在裤子里呢？
And if I was to say you shit in your pants because of a cowardly soul...
我打赌 你马上就会拔出那把手枪打死我
I bet you'd show me with that pistol quick and shoot me dead.
是不是这样？
Isn't that so?
可能吧，我猜想
Maybe, I guess.
但其实...
But the fact...
是我没有带什么火器
...is I ain't carrying no firearm.
起来
Get up.
来
Come on.
这是打什么的，蛇还是什么？
What's this for, snakes and such?
对
Yeah.
我们这里可没什么蛇，亨德肖特先生
We don't have any snakes in here, Mr. Hendershot.
哦，你们有的
Well, you have.
它没装弹，要么就是弹药湿了？
It ain't loaded or... .Powder's wet?
你看，博尚先生？
You see, Mr. Beauchamp?
这就是我说的那种垃圾！
This is the kind of trash I was speaking of!
你在繁荣之地的酒吧里到处都能发现这种人！
You'll find this kind in all the saloons in all your prosperous communities!
在维奇托！
Wichita!
一直到夏延!
Over in Cheyenne!
在阿比林!
Abilene!
但你在大威士忌镇里找不到他们
But you wouldn't find them in the town of Big Whiskey.
快！你知道该对小比尔说什么
Hurry up! You know what to tell Bill.
- 你们仔细找那棵独松  - 独松
-You guys look sharp for that lone pine. - Lone pine
错过那松树，你们就找不到了
You miss the pike, you ain't find it.
好，别管衬衣了！穿上他妈的靴子！
Ok, never mind the shirt now! Put the fucking boots on!
该死
Damn
威尔怎么办？
What about Will?
我们拿威尔怎么办？
What are we going to do about Will?
快走，小子！
Move, Kid!
希望那些马还在那儿！
Let's hope them horses are still there!
让这人出去，W.W
Let the man out, W.W.
他想把大威士忌镇的殷勤好客留在身后
He's desiring to leave the hospitality of Big Whiskey behind him.
轻点，小比尔，她还要工作
Easy Little Bill, she's gonna work.
她一次要赚一美元呢
She's got to turn a dollar a time.
如果他们只是上来打炮，怎么会从后窗跑了？
If they were just here for the fuck. How come they lit out the back window?
他们在顶楼看见你在打他们的朋友
On the garret hey seen you beating on their friend.
他们只是来打台球的，小比尔，实话
They just come for the billiards, Little Bill, honest.
台球？
Billiards?!
你说他们只是经过这里？
You mean they were just passing through here?
他们要去布福德堡
They was going to Fort Buford.
你刚刚毒打了一个无辜的人
You kicked the shit out of an innocent man.
无辜？
Innocent?
哪方面无辜？
Innocent of what?
老天，威尔
Jesus, Will
老天，内德
Jesus, Ned
你以前干过这个？
You done this before?
很多次
Plenty times.
他的手枪肯定是卡壳了
His pistol must've jammed.
这里，蜡烛拿近一点，我看不见
Here. Bring that candle a little closer. I can't see.
如果它没卡壳，他不会被打成这样
He wouldn't take no beating like that if it hadn't jammed.
他不可能不开枪打他们就算了
He wouldn't give it over and not shoot them one.
他看起来不妙
He don't look so good.
他连手枪都没拔？
He didn't even pull his pistol?
对，他没你那么牛逼，小子
Yeah, well, he ain't as tough as you, Kid.
对，至少我会拔枪
Yeah, well, at lest I'd have pulled my pistol man.
你当然会！
You did!
从那女士身上拔出来，爬出该死的窗户
Out of the lady and out the god damn window!
那是你的主意！我想返回去...
That was your idea! I wanna roll back...
我们得走了
We got to go.
什么？就走？
What? Already?
亲，我都准备好再收一份预付款了
Hey, darling, I'm ready for another advance.
你还没收到钱就花光了
You'll use it all up before you can get it.
事情没办成，再没有预付款了
No more advances on what's you ain't done yet.
甜心，我们只是在等天气好转！一旦天气好了...
Sweetheart, we're just waiting on this weather to clear! Once the weather get...
我们需要更多食物！
We're going to need more food!
大概吃三天的
About three days' worth.
三天？
Three days?
内德，我们明天就能杀了他们
Ned, we can kill them tomorrow.
没有他，我谁也不杀
I don't kill nobody without him.
我们不需要他，我们两个能做
We don't need him! The two of us can do it.
况且...
Besides...
他什么也不是，只是个受伤的养猪农民
he ain't nothing but a broken-down pig farmer.
早上我们有人会送来吃的
One of us'll bring food in the morning.
我们还会给你们带一些威士忌！
We'll bring you some whiskey too!
如果有药也拿来吧！
And some medicine if you got any!
听到他这样你不觉得恶心吗？
Don't it make you sick hearing him like that?
你们这些女士们别担心！
Don't you ladies worry!
我和内德会为你们杀了那两个混蛋的！
Me and Ned will kill them two sons of bitches for you!
克劳迪娅
Claudia.
威尔
Will
- 克劳迪娅  - 克劳迪娅不在这儿
- Claudia.  - Claudia's not here.
是你吗，内德？
Is that you, Ned?
我看见他了，内德
I seen him Ned.
我看见死亡天使了
I seen the Angel of Death.
我看见一条河，内德.
I seen a river, Ned.
他长着一双蛇眼
He's got snake eyes.
谁，威尔？谁长着蛇眼？
Who, Will?  Who's got snake eyes?
是死亡天使
It's the Angel of Death.
内德
Ned
我害怕死
I'm scared of dying.
放松，搭档，放松
Easy, partner. Easy.
我也看见克劳迪娅了
I seen Claudia too.
那是好事，威尔，见到克劳迪娅是好事，对吗？
That's good Will. It's good to saw Claudia, ain't it?
她脸上爬满虫子
Her face was all covered with worms.
内德，我害怕
Ned, I'm scared.
我要死了
I'm dying.
不要告诉任何人
No, don't tell nobody.
不要告诉我的孩子...
Don't tell my kids...
我以前做的事情，你听见没？
none of the things I done. You hear?
好的，威尔
All right, Will.
他要死了，对吧？
He's gonna die, ain't he?
也许
Maybe.
假如他真死了呢？
Supposing he does?
我们会埋了他
We'll bury him.
我不是这个意思，内德
That ain't what I mean, Ned.
你是说我会不会帮你去杀那两个牛仔？
You mean will I help you kill them cowboys?
我自己认不出他们两个
I can't spot them myseIf.
但你行
But you could.
那个大块头，你能在半里外就认出他来，我打赌
That big bastard, you could spot him a haIf-mile off, I bet.
如果我找出来了？
And if I spot him?
那我就骑马近前去开枪
Then I ride up close and shoot him.
就这样？
Just like that?
我跟你说过我是一个厉害杀手，我以前做过
I told you I'm a damn killer. I done it before.
我当杀手反正比他强多了
I'm more of a killer than he is anyhow.
是吗？
Yeah?
对
Yeah
我以为你是个天使！
I thought you was an angel.
你没死
You ain't dead.
几个大家伙...
Some big fellow...
把我踢得半死
kicked the hell out of me.
我现在样子一定像你一样
I must look like you now.
你样子一点不像我，先生
You don't look nothing like me, mister.
无意冒犯
No offense meant.
你一定是被牛仔割伤的那个
You got to be the one those cowboys cut up.
我的搭档，内德和那小子...
My partners, Ned and that Kid...
在附近吗？
...they around?
看见你退烧，他们就出去打探了
They went out scouting when they saw your fever broke.
打探？
Scouting?
就在巴提外面...
Out to the Bar T...
去找他们
...looking for them.
我在这里多久了？
How long I been here?
三天了
Three days.
你饿不饿...
Are you hungry or... .
三天？
Three days?
我本来应该...
I ought to be... .
我以为我死了
I thought I was gone.
我一般不会注意这种山区里的...
I wouldn't normally pay no notice to high country like this...
树的，但我现在明显注意到了
...trees, but I'm sure noticing now.
还以为我肯定要死了
Thought I was dying for sure.
我带来你的帽子
I brought your hat.
你把它落在格里利店了
You left it down at Greely's.
谢谢
Thanks.
那个治安官...
That sheriff...
他还在找我吗？
He still looking for me?
小比尔？
Little Bill?
不，他认为你们往南走了
No, he thinks you went south.
你真的要去杀死那两个牛仔？
Are you really going to kill them cowboys?
我想是的
I guess.
还有赏金，对吧？
Still a payment coming, isn't there?
另外两个人，你的朋友...
Them other two, your friends...
他们一直在拿赏金预付款
they been taking advances on the payment.
预付款？
Advances?
免费玩
Free ones.
免费玩？
Free ones?
艾丽丝和丝丝让他们免费玩
Alice and Silky been giving them free ones.
我明白了
I see.
你想要一次免费的吗？
Would you like a free one?
不，我...
No, I...
我看不用了
I guess not.
我…我不是说跟我，我是说...
I didn't mean with me. I meant...
艾丽丝和丝丝会高兴让你免费玩，如果你想的话
Alice and Silky would be happy to give you a free one if you wanted one.
我就是这意思
That's all I meant.
我并不是说...
I didn't mean...
我不想要免费玩是因为你被割伤什么的
I didn't want a free one because you been cut up and all.
那天我说的，你样子象我，不是真的
What I said the other day about you looking like me, that ain't true.
你不象我这么丑
You ain't ugly like me.
只是因为我们俩都有疤痕
It's just that we both got scars.
你是个漂亮女人，如果我想要免费的...
You're a beautiful woman and if I wanted a free one...
我想我更愿意跟你而不是跟她们两个
I'd want it with you I guess more than them other two.
只是我...
It's just that...
我不能，因为我妻子
l can't on account of my wife.
你妻子？
Your wife?
对
Yeah.
你明白了？
You see?
我为此钦佩你
I admire you for that.
因为对你妻子的忠贞这些
For being true to your wife and all.
我认识很多男人...
I've known a lot of men...
他们没有
who weren't.
对，我想是的
Yeah, I suppose.
她在堪萨斯吗？
Is she back in Kansas?
是的
Yeah.
对，她在照看我的孩子
Yeah, she's watching over my young ones.
停下！
Hang on
拿该死的烙铁来！
Get the damn iron!
- 戴维！ - 操
-Davey - Fuck
来，戴维，来，抓住它
Come on, Davey. Come on! Go get him.
天啊，伙计们！
Jesus, fellas!
天啊，兄弟们，我的腿断了！
Jesus, boys, my leg's broke!
我动不了了，兄弟们！
I'm pinned, boys!
最好了结他，内德
Better finish him, Ned.
他没死？你没打中他？
He ain't dead? You didn't get him?
他打中那孩子的马
He got the boy's horse.
最好在他跑出射程之前结果他
Better finish him before he gets clear.
他们在岩石后，戴维仔
Get behind them rocks, Davey boy.
过那边去，戴维！
Get over there, Davey!
发生了什么？没杀死他？
What happened? He ain't killed?!
怎么了？
What's going on?
他藏在岩石里，我们打不到他
He gets in those rocks, we won't get him.
除非我们下去
Unless we go down there.
什么岩石？
What rocks?
你干嘛不开枪？发生什么事了，内德？
Why don't you shoot? What's going on, Ned?
你怎么不开枪？
Why ain't you gonna shoot?
威尔
Will
用这个我不太在行
I ain't very good with one of these.
继续走，戴维！岩石！继续走！
Keep going, Davey! The rocks! Keep going
你打中他没？
Did you get him?
他在哪？
Where is he?
我还能开几枪？
How many more shots do I have?
内德，该死的，我还能开几枪？
Ned, god damn it. How many more shots do I have?
两枪
Two.
继续，戴维
Go, Davey.
你打中他没？
Did you get him?
拿着，重新装弹
Here, reload this.
你没打中他
You missed him.
我打中他了
I got him.
他打中我了，兄弟们
He shot me boys.
他没死
He ain't killed.
他们打中我了
They shot me.
可能死了，可能没死
Maybe, maybe not.
打穿了他的内脏，我认为
Got him through the gut, I think.
你认为他会死吗？
You think he's gonna die?
你认为我们杀了他？
You think we killed him?
他们打中我了，兄弟们
They shot me, boys.
是的
Yeah.
我们杀了他，我猜
We killed him, I guess.
我要死了，兄弟们!
I'm dying, boys!
那你就不该割女人，你这混蛋！
Then you shouldn't have cut up no woman, you asshole!
天啊，我好渴！
Jesus, I'm so thirsty!
斯利姆！
Slim
斯利姆，给我...给我点水，拜托
Slim, give me...give me some water, please!
拜托，斯利姆！
Please, Slim!
我在流血，斯利姆!
I'm bleeding, Slim!
给我点水，拜托!
Give me some water please.
给他喝口水，该死的！
Give him a drink of water, goddamn it!
给我口水喝，拜托你们了
Give me a drink of water, would you, please!
你们给不给他一口水？看在基督的份上！
Would you give him a drink of water, for chris sake!
我们不会开枪的
We ain't going to shoot!
你们不会开枪？
You ain't going to shoot?
不会
No.
等一下，戴维仔
Hold on, Davey-boy!
我现在过来
Here I come now!
不要开枪打我，混蛋！
Don't you shoot me, you bastards!
该死
Damn!
糟糕
Shit!
戴维
Davey
他们给他喝水？
They take him water?
对
Yeah.
天啊，约翰尼，他们射中了他！
Jesus, Johnny! They shot him!
戴维，坚持一下！
Davey, hold on now!
你们这些混账杀人犯！你们杀了我们戴维仔!
You murdering bastards! You killed our Davey-boy!
我们什么时候原路折返？
When will we double back?
还有一程
After a ways.
我不去
Not me.
我从这里回堪萨斯
I'm heading back down to Kansas.
我们得先杀了另外那个
We got to kill the other one first.
内德，运气好，我们黄昏或早上就能找到他
Ned, with any luck, we'll find him by nightfall or in the morning.
我们杀了他，然后回去，带着钱
We'll shoot him and head back with the money.
你想要这支斯宾塞吗，威尔？
Do you want the Spencer, Will?
现在可不是退出的时候，内德
It's ain't no time to quit, Ned.
对，你拿不到你那份了，内德
Yeah, you'll lose your share, Ned.
闭嘴！
Shut up!
回头见，威尔   再见小子
I'll see you, Will. So long, Kid.
内德
Ned
给
Here.
你知道我反正用不好这玩意儿
You know I ain't no good with that damn thing anyhow.
我和那小子去那个牧场，找到并杀了他
Look, me and the Kid'll head over to that ranch and when we find him we'll shoot him.
我们来跟你会合，拿上我们的钱，一起回家
We'll meet up with you, get our money, and all heads back together.
如果他没回牧场呢，威尔？
Suppose he don't go back to the ranch, Will?
他不会去镇上，我估计他不会待在野外开阔地
He ain't going into town. I figure he won't stay out in the open country.
他会藏在那牧场里
He'll hole up at that ranch.
我不等了
Well I ain't waiting.
我会去看看你的孩子，等你回来
I'll look in on your young ones until you back.
嘿，内德
Hey, Ned.
不用管那小子说的那些关于钱的话
Don't pay attention with the Kid said about the money and all.
我会带回你那份
I'll bring your share.
小子尽胡说
Kid's full of shit.
小比尔
Little Bill.
我在上面做些修理
I just doing some repairs up here.
他们杀了其中一个牛仔
They killed one of them cowboys.
糟糕
Shit!
帕森斯说他看见三个人，就在日出之后，往东走
Parsons said how he seen three men, right after sunup, headed down east.
一个骑暗褐色马，另一个骑红斑灰马
One was on a dun and another was on a flea-bitten grey.
他不知道第三个骑什么，可能是阿帕卢萨马
He didn't know what the third one was on, could've been an Appaloosa.
因为他是迎着阳光看
‘cause he's looking right into the sun.
小比尔，阿莫斯说去问问 县里愿不愿出那些马的草料钱
Little Bill, Amos says to ask if the county will pay for feed for all the horses.
威瑟斯彭说他不会赊帐卖给我们.33子弹了
Witherspoon says won't sell us no more 33 shells without pay.
见鬼，用我的狗去抵债吧
Hell, use my dogs!
那么县里必须负责
Then the county's got to be responsible.
- 说得对  - 是啊
-That's right. -Yeah.
别操心那些马了，胖子
Don't warry about them horses, Fatty.
你就赶到巴提去，确保另一个牛仔...
you just get on out there to the Bar T and make sure that other cowboy...
- 待在那儿，别在这里暴露他自己 - 好
-stays put and don't expose himseIf here. -All right
我没想到他们会真的干了
I didn't think they'd really do it.
你以为他们从堪萨斯来，就为了操我们
You think they come clear up from Kansas to fuck us?
不，但是...
No, but...
那个小子，他只是个男孩，另外那个...
That Kid, he's just a boy and the other one...
威尔，那个好人，对他的妻子真是忠贞...
Will, the nice one, being so true to his wife... .
妻子？他没有妻子
Wife? He ain't got no wife.
- 不，他有的，他...  - 我告诉你，他没有什么妻子
Yes, he does. He... -I tell you. He ain't got no wife.
反正在世的是没有
Not above ground, anyways.
杀人犯妓女！
Murdering whores!
他自找的...
He had it coming...
他罪有应得自找的
He had it coming for what he done.
另外一个也是
And the other one too!
他们两个都罪有应得！
Both of them for what they done!
我们抓到一个！
We got one!
我们抓到一个！治安官，就在牛溪外面！
We got one, Sheriff! Out by Cow Creek!
他还活着吗？
Is he alive?
是的
Hell, yeah!
我们巴提的一帮人出去找，因为他们杀了我们的人
Bunch of us boys from Bar T went out looking because they killed one of our own.
正遇上那混蛋骑着一匹杂色马向南走
Come across the bastard on a roan heading south.
他承认了？
He admit it?
没有，我想他会很快会的
No. But I guess he will soon enough.
他带着一支斯宾塞来复枪
Had a Spencer rifle on him.
那些牛仔揍他了吗？
Those cawboys messing him up?
一点点吧我想
Little bit I guess.
好吧，克莱德，安迪
All right. Clyde! Andy!
快去那儿，再查查另外两个怎么了
Get out there. Find out what happened to those other two fellows!
在外面看见什么了，巴克?
Did you see anything out there, Buck?
当然看见了，看见200多号人拿着来复枪
Hell, yes I did! Seen about 200 fellows packing rifles.
包围这那地方，说想要快手迈克的屁股
Got the place surrounded. Say they want Quick Mike's ass.
我说，“多少钱？”
I said, "How much?"
他们说，“大约五...”  我说，“美元吗？“
They says, "About five. " I said, "Dollars?"
他们说，“分”
They said, "Cents. "
我说，“成交”
I said, "Sold. "
我不担心
Well, I ain't worried!
因为我自己有保护措施
Because I got me some protection.
- 告诉你另外两个在哪没？ - 没
-Tell you where them others is? -Nope
说了姓名吗？
Give any names?
只告诉我们他的名字，内德・朗特里
Tell us nothing but only his name, Ned Roundtree.
带他进去
Bring him in.
内德
Ned
你会告诉我和这位博尚先生...
You'll want to tell me and Mr. Beauchamp here...
关于你那两个恶棍朋友的一切
all about your two villainous friends I guess.
我会高兴听见那俩狗杂种的名字和行踪
I'll be glad to hear the names and whereabouts of those son of a bitches.
时机成熟
Sure is ripe.
对
Yeah.
等一下会更成熟
Going to get a lot riper.
你觉得他还在里面么？
You think he's still in there?
是的，他在里面
Yeah. He's in there.
对，他正守着自己的屎 好像那就是钱
Yeah, he's holding on to his shit like it was money.
他在里面
He's in there.
你看见他就马上告诉我
You tell me right off if you see him.
好
Yap
你自己不会开枪打他，对吧？
You ain't gonna shoot him your own seIf, are you?
你可以开枪打他
You can shoot him.
现在，内德，你和昆西先生还有...
Now, Ned, you and Mr. Quincy and... .
那个年轻人叫什么名字？
What was the young fellow's name?
埃洛伊
Elroy.
埃洛伊・塔特
Elroy Tate.
不，刚才你可不是这么说的
No, that's not what you said.
不是就见鬼了！
Hell, if it ain't!
不，你说...
No, you said...
"埃洛伊・昆西 来自麦迪逊哈特 还有...
"Elroy Quincy out of Medicine Hat...
亨利・塔特 来自夏延”
and Henry Tate out of Cheyenne. "
见鬼，我刚才说错了
Hell, if I did.
查理
Charley
把那晚在客栈里跟他们搞的妓女带来
Go get them whores that pumped these boys that night at the store.
草莓艾丽丝和丝丝？
Strawberry Alice and Silky?
对，快去，把她们带来
Yeah. Go on and get them!
去吧
Go on
内德
Ned
那些妓女会说跟你不同的谎话
Them whores are going to tell different lies than you.
要是她们的谎话跟你的谎话不一样...
And when their lies ain't the same as your lies... .
我不会伤害女人
I ain't going to hurt no woman.
但我会伤害你
But I'm going to hurt you.
不象刚才那么温和...
Not gentle like before...
会很糟
...but bad.
你去哪？
Where you going?
去茅厕
Going out the shithouse.
我打完这把跟你去
Let me finish hand with you.
怎么，要保护我上大号？
What? You gonna protect me while I take a dump?
你会被伏击
You'll get bushwhacked.
我就冲他们放屁
I'll fart on them.
- 我跟你去 - 好，你可以替我擦屁股，老渴
-I'll go with you. -Yeah, you can wipe my ass, Thirsty.
见他的鬼吧，他没礼貌，活该挨枪
Hell with him. He ain't polite, he should get shot.
是他吗？
Is that him?
对，是他
Yeah, that's him.
好了，小子，去杀他，他是你的了
All right, Kid. Go get him. He's all yours.
暗杀者
Assassins!
开枪呀！
Shoot him!
不
No
不不
No, no
快啊，该死的！
Come on, goddamn it!
你干掉他了？
Did you get him?
对
Yeah.
掩护我
Cover me.
我看不见他们！
I can't see them!
只管开枪，该死
Just shoot, damn you.
象不象以前的日子，威尔？
Was it like that in the old days, Will?
大家都骑着马，开枪...
Everybody riding out, shooting...
到处是烟，乡亲们大叫，子弹到处飞？
smoke all over, folks yelling, bullets whizzing by?
我想是的
I guess so.
该死，我以为他们会追上我们
Shit, I thought they'd get us.
我甚至有点害怕
I was even scared a little.
只有一会儿
For a minute.
那些日子你曾害怕过吗？
You ever scared in them days?
我不记得了
I can't remember.
大部分时候我都醉着
I was drunk most of the time.
我对那烂人开了三枪
I shot that fucker three times!
他在拉屎，去拿手枪，我连续开枪
He was taking a shit, went for his pistol and I blazed away.
第一枪...
First shot...
我正中他的胸口
I got him right in the chest.
我说威尔
Say, Will
说
Yeah.
那是第一个
That was the first.
第一个什么？
First one what?
我杀的第一个人
First one I ever killed.
是吗
Yeah?
你知道我以前说我杀过五个人？
You know how I said I shot five men?
不是真的
It weren't true.
那个拿刀追我的墨西哥人
That Mexican come after me with the knife?
我只是用铲子伤了他的腿，我也没杀了他
I just busted his leg with a shovel. I didn't kill him or nothing neither.
你今天的的确确杀死了那个人
Well, you sure killed the hell out of that fellow today.
见鬼，对
Hell, yeah!
我把他杀得死透了，对吧？
Killed the hell out of him, didn't I?
三枪，他在拉屎
Three shots and he was taking a shit.
喝口酒，小子
Take a drink, Kid.
耶稣基督
Jesus Christ!
看着不真实
It don't seem real.
他就那么不再呼吸了，永远
How he ain't never breathing again, ever.
他就那么死了
How he's dead.
另外一个也是
And the other one too.
只是扣了一下扳机
On account of pulling a trigger.
这是件可怕的事，杀人
It's a hell of a thing, killing a man.
你夺走他所有的一切...
You take away all he's got...
以及他将有的一切
...and all he's ever gonna have.
对
Yeah.
我想是他们是自找的
I guess they had it coming.
我们都是自找的，小子
We all have it coming, Kid.
我一直盯着你，看见你没被跟踪
I was watching you, seen that you weren't followed.
丝丝和阿贞，她们骑马向东走，两个副治安官跟着她们
Silky and Faith rode off to the east and two deputies was following them.
来
Here.
你要帮我清点这东西吗，小子？
You want to help me count this stuff, Kid?
我相信你，威尔
I trust you, Will.
不要过于相信我
Don't go trusting me too much.
实际上，我们要把内德那份一起算
ln fact, we'll give Ned his share together.
你就知道我没有对你藏一手
You'll know I ain't holding out on you.
内德那份？
Ned's share?
对
Yeah.
他往南边走了，我们会赶上他
He went south. We'll catch up to him.
内德，他死了
Ned, he's dead.
你什么意思，“他死了”？
What do you mean, his dead?
他昨天向南走了，他没死
He went south yesterday. He ain't dead.
他们杀了他，我以为你们知道
They killed him. I thought you knew that.
没有人杀了内德!
Nobody killed Ned!
他谁也没杀，他昨天向南走了
He didn't kill anyone. He went south yesterday!
为什么会有人杀内德?
Why would anybody kill Ned?
谁杀了他？
Who killed him?
小比尔
Little Bill.
巴提的人抓住了他，然后小比尔…
The Bar T boys caught him, and Little Bill...
他...他打他
he beat him up.
他逼他回答问题，又打他，然后内德就死了
He was making him answer questions, and beating him up. Then Ned just died.
他们弄了个告示在他身上，说他就是凶手
They got a sign on him says he was a killer.
他们弄告示在他身上？
They got a sign on him?
在格里利店前面
ln front of Greely's.
告示贴在他身上 在格里利店前面
A sign on him in front of Greely's!
小比尔问的问题...
These questions Little Bill was asking...
是什么问题？
...what kind were they?
关于你和他在哪里
About where you and him was.
后来怎样？
Then what?
一个牛仔进来
A cowboy come in
说你们在巴提的茅厕杀了快手迈克
saying you killed Quick Mike in the shithouse of Bar T.
所以小比尔杀了他，是因为我们干的事情？
So Little Bill killed him for what we done?
不是有意的
Not on purpose.
不过他打他打得更厉害了
But he started hurting him worse.
逼他说出来
Making him tell stuff.
开始，内德什么也不说
First, Ned wouldn't say nothing.
后来，小比尔把他打惨了
And then Little Bill hurt him so bad
他就说了你是谁
he said who you was.
他说你其实是威廉・曼尼，来自密苏里
He said how you was really William Munny out of Missouri.
小比尔说，“是那个威廉・曼尼，69年炸毁铁路密苏里铁路...
Little Bill said, "The same William Munny, the one dynamited the railroad Missouri in '69,
杀死不少妇女儿童”
killing women and children and all?"
内德说 你做过很多比那更坏的事
Ned said you done a lot worse than that.
说你比威尔・邦尼更冷血
Said you was more cold-blooded than Will Bonney.
还有如果他再打内德的话...
Said how if he hurt Ned again...
你会来杀了他
you was gonna come to kill him
就像你70年杀死联邦执法官那样
like you killed the U.S. Marshal in '70.
这没吓倒小比尔，是吧？
That didn't scare Little Bill, did it?
没有，先生
No, sir.
把你的斯科菲尔德给我
Give me your Schofield.
要干嘛，威尔？
What for, Will?
把它给我
Give it to me.
好，当然
Yeah. Sure
你想要就留着吧
You want it, keep it.
我再也不会用它了
I would never gonna use it again.
我再也不会杀人了
I won't kill nobody no more.
我不像你，威尔
I ain't like you, Will.
你最好骑马回去，小姐
You better ride on back, Miss.
来，全拿去吧，都是你的
Go on, keep it, all of it. It's yours.
你的眼镜和漂亮衣服呢？
What about spectacles and fancy clothes?
我想我宁愿又瞎又破烂，也比死了强
I guess I'd rather be blind and ragged than dead.
你没有必要担心，小子
You don't have to worry, Kid.
我不会杀你
I ain't going to kill you.
你是我唯一的朋友
You're the only friend I got.
给
Here.
拿着这些钱，把我那一半和...
Take this money and give my half
内德那一半 给我的孩子
and Ned's half to my kids.
告诉他们 如果我一周内没回去
Tell them if I ain't back in a week,
就把一半给“两树萨莉”
they give haIf to Sally Two Trees.
其余的你拿着，去买副眼镜吧
You keep the rest. Get those spectacles now.
你要去杀小比尔，对吗？
You're gonna kill Little Bill, ain't you?
你别让乡亲们看见
You stay clear of folks you see.
会有不少人要出来吊死你
There'll be a lot out to hang you.
去吧
Get going.
（这就是在这里搞暗杀的下场）
好了，我再说最后一次，所以别再问我
All right, I'm going to say this just one more time, make clear, so don't ask me again!
今天参与的人，由县里出钱喝一杯
Those who on posse today's  got one drink coming from the county budget!
昨天巡逻的人，也有一杯
And those who rode yesterday get one for that too.
等一下！
Hold it!
那就是两杯了
Now that's...that's two!
但这以后你们自掏腰包，听到没瘦皮？
But after that, it comes out of your own pocket! You hear, Skinny?
- 是，长官  - 好
-Yes, sir. -All right
我们明天早早出发
We'll pull out early in the morning.
我们要追这些家伙到德克萨斯
We'll chase these fellows clear down to Texas,
所以不要花太多自己的钱
so don't spend too much of your own money.
我们分四队!
We'll divide up into four parties!
我们要搜遍所有的农场、小道
And we'll hit all the farms, trails...
画个大圈
to make a big circle.
我们一定会碰上几个人，见过那些...
And we're bound to come across somebody who seen these...
…黄鼠狼
skunks.
哪个哥们是这狗窝的主人？
Who's the fello owns this shithole?
你，胖子
You, fat man.
说话
Speak up.
呃，这地方是我的
I own this establishment.
我从格里利那里买的，一千美元
I bought it from Greely for $1 ,000.
你最好把外面清理一下
You better clear out of there.
是，先生
Yes, sir
先停下！
Just hold it up there!
慢着
Hold it!
先生，你是个狗娘养的懦夫！
Well, sir, you are a cowardly son of a bitch!
你刚枪杀了一个没有武器的人
You just shot an unarmed man.
他本该武装好的...
He should've armed himself...
既然他用我的朋友来装饰他的酒吧
if he's gonna decorated his saloon with my friend.
你就是密苏里的威廉・曼尼...
You'd be William Munny out of Missouri...
妇孺杀手
killer of women and children.
正是
That's right.
我杀过女人和孩子
I've killed women and children.
杀过几乎所有能走能爬的东西
Killed just about everything that walks or crawls, one type or other.
我来这里杀你了，小比尔.
And I'm here to kill you, Little Bill.
为你对内德所做的
For what you did to Ned.
你们几个最好让开
You boys better move away.
好了，先生们
All right, gentlemen.
他只剩一颗子弹
He's got one barrel left.
等他开了枪后，拿出你们的手枪...
When he fires it, take out your pistols...
把他打成破烂，他就该那样！
and shoot him down like the mangy scoundrel he is!
哑火了！杀了这狗娘养的！
Misfire! Kill the son of a bitch!
不想被杀的人，最好从后面出去
Any man don't want to get killed, better clear on out the back.
老天爷
Wow, God
我中枪了，我中枪了
I'm shot! I'm shot!
你没中枪
You ain't shot.
哦，请别
Oh, please
我没有枪，我没有武器
I don't have a gun. I am not armed.
捡起那支来复枪
Pick up that rifle.
捡起来
Pick it up.
还有子弹
Shells too.
天啊
God
你杀了小比尔
You killed Little Bill.
你确实没武器吗？
Sure you ain't armed?
没有，你瞧
No, look.
我没有，我没有枪
I'm not. I don't have a gun.
我从不带枪
I've never had a gun.
我写东西，我是个作家
I write. I'm a writer!
- 作家？ - 对
-A writer? -Yeah
- 写信什么的？  - 不，书
-Letters and such? -No, books.
书
Books.
我不敢相信，你杀了五个人
l don't believe it, you killed five men.
单枪匹马
Single-handed.
是啊
Yeah.
那是…那是支斯宾塞来复枪，对吧？
That's a...that's a Spencer rifle, right?
没错
That's right.
谁是第一个？
Who's the first?
你先杀的谁？
Who'd you kill first?
“遇到数量占优的敌人...
"When confronted by superior numbers...
有经验的枪手 总是先杀枪法最好的人"
an experienced gunfighter will fire on the best shot first. "
是这样吗？
Is that so?
对，小比尔跟我说的，你可能是先杀了他
Little Bill said that. You probably killed him first.
这个顺序是我运气好
l was lucky in the order.
不过杀人的时候我总是运气好
But I'm always lucky when it comes to killing folks.
那么
And so
下一个呢？是克莱德，对吧？
Who was next? It's Clyde, right?
你一定是杀了克莱德，或者是副治安官安迪，是他吗...
You must be killed Clyde, or it could've been Deputy Andy, wasn't he? Or...
我只能告诉你谁会是最后一个
All I can tell you is who's gonna be last.
我不该得此下场
I don't deserve this.
像这样死
To die like this.
我在盖房子呢
I was building a house.
“该不该”和这没关系
Deserve's got nothing to do with it.
我在地狱见你，威廉・曼尼
I'll see you in hell, William Munny.
对
Yeah.
好了，我要出来了！
All right, I'm coming out!
我在外面看见任何人，我就杀了他！
Any man I see out there, I'm gonna kill him!
有人对我开枪...
Anyone takes a shot at me...
我不单要杀他，还要杀他的老婆、他所有的朋友
I'm not only going to kill him, but his wife and all his friends.
烧了他该死的房子
and burn his damn house down!
最好没人开枪
Nobody better shoot!
查理，上啊，开枪打他
Hey, Charley, go ahead. Shoot him!
我不能
I can't.
不行，见鬼，我不是副治安官
Hell, no! I ain't no deputy!
你们最好安葬内德
You better bury Ned right!
你们最好别再割或是伤害那些妓女！
You better not cut up nor otherwise harm no whores!
不然我会回来 杀死你们每一个狗娘养的
Or I'll come back and kill every one of you sons of bitches.
几年后，安东尼娅・费瑟斯太太
经过艰辛旅程来到霍奇曼县
探访她唯一女儿最后的安息地
威廉・曼尼和孩子们早已消失
有人说去了旧金山
传言说在那里做纺织品生意 兴旺发达
没有任何记载可以对费瑟斯太太解释：
为什么她唯一的女儿
会嫁给一个知名的盗贼、谋杀犯
一个恶名远扬，凶残成性的人
导演、制片：克林特・伊斯特伍德
（奇连伊士活、东木头大人...）